This month's challenge is the 100 rep
back extension challenge. You can use
these in either a 45 degree
hyperextension bench or a horizontal one
like a glute ham developer. Either one
works. Now, I've trained around 50
different women who have been able to
pull off 100 non-stop repetitions of
back extensions, but they didn't start
out that way. They start off doing
around 20, but over the month, you're
going to build up to around 100 reps.
All right, here's how you're going to do
the exercise. Make sure that when you
get into position, the pad is not too
low and not too high. It should be right
at the hips. Um,
when you bend over, you want to be able
to achieve full hip extension without
causing you to round over. So, you want
this right at the hips. Here's how
people screw it up. They will come down
like this and round their back. And then
as they come up, they will extend their
spine like this. and you see them hyper
extend their spine because they've been
told that this is a back extension. They
think they should feel it in their back.
Well, it's actually a hip extension. And
if you need to think of it, think of it
as a glute extension because you were
using your glutes. So, you are going to
come down. You're going to fold your
arms like this. Come down into get a big
stretch in the hamstrings. And now, when
I come up, I think of pushing my hips
into the bench and I squeeze the glutes
as hard as I can up top. So come down
just like that. Squeeze the glutes.
Notice I am in full extension right
here. This is a strong My glutes are
turned on. I have a strong glute
squeeze. I do not come up to here and I
don't stop short to here. My upper back
might round a little bit because of the
glute squeeze, because of the posterior
pelvic tilt. That's fine. But what you
want to do is maintain a normal cadence.
So here's what 10 repetitions looks
like.
Okay. One thing you will notice my feet
here are turned out just a little bit.
You can externally rotate them. Again,
you're not using load, just body weight.
Fold the arms. make the movement at the
hips. You will feel it in the glutes.
You'll also feel the hamstrings. Your
hamstrings will get a little sore
because they get stretched, but you not
should not feel it all in the back. If
you do, you're probably doing it wrong.
Anyway, make sure you go to the blog
where I have the schedule laid out. I
think you'll be performing 12 different
body weight sessions throughout the
month with the last session culminating
with the 100 reps. Okay, thanks for
watching.